I know this person.
He's all brawn and no brains.
I have my own ways.
Okay.
I'll leave it to you.
Remember.
If you can't convince him,
you will die with him.
Yes.
I didn't expect it.
I didn't expect Tianyuan Zhengxiong to return halfway.
He caught us off guard.
Chief Wu hasn't returned yet.
I'm afraid he's in danger.
Baozi, where is Liu Banjin?
To cover our safe retreat,
Master Liu stayed in Qinglong Stronghold.
I think he knows the secret passage quite well.
I hope he will be fine.
I hope so.
Baozi.
Something happened.
Xiaoni is missing.
When did this happen?
Probably when I was changing Yuanshangfei's dressing.
She was sleeping all day today,
so I didn't pay much attention.
When you just got back,
Ying'er asked, and then I realized she was gone.
The treasure map is gone too.
Did Xiaoni know about the treasure map?
I didn't tell her,
but she saw that parchment.
I only said it was Second Uncle Huo's relic,
and she even specifically helped me put it away.
Could Xiaoni have taken it?
Major Tahara.
A woman is outside saying her surname is He.
She wants to see you.
Surname He?
Yes.
Quick, bring her in.
Yes, sir.
So it's Miss He.
I hope you've been well.
Does your word still count?
Of course it does.
As long as you get what I want,
I will let your father go so you can run away together.
I want to see my father.
Okay.
Give me the item first,
and I'll take you to see your father.
I finally
got it.
Men!
Major.
Go quickly
and invite Professor Takeshita here.
Yes, sir.
I have done what I promised you.
What about your promise to me?
I promised not to kill your father,
and I kept my word.
If you want your father to live,
steal that map and give it to me.
I'll guarantee your safety
and reunite you.
You clearly said
that if I gave you the map,
you would let me and my father go.
You broke your promise.
Give me back the map.
Give it back.
Guards!
Tian,
you lied to me.
To save my father,
I betrayed everyone.
Now,
I have nothing left.
You caused all of this.
It's all your fault.
I'll kill you.
Let me go! I'll kill you!
You lied to me!
Go!
Bastard! I'll kill you!
Let me go! I'll kill you!
Let me go!
This map is different from the first two.
It looks quite strange.
Apart from being blank,
it only has a few holes.
Was it intentionally destroyed?
That shouldn't be the case.
That girl said
she stole it from Shangguan Ying.
If it really was damaged,
there'd be no use in them keeping it.
Then this third map is completely blank.
What does it mean?
Takeshita.
I believe this map must be real.
She wouldn't dare use her father's life
to play such a joke.
The first two maps combine into one.
This third map,
apart from being blank
and having a few holes,
has no connection to the first two.
It must be fake.
Could I have been tricked by them again?
Bastard!
Tahara, come take a look.
There are words in this cave.
Daifeng.
Five li.
South.
Toad Cave.
What does this mean?
According to Chinese writing habits,
the sequence should be:
South of Daifeng,
five li, Toad Cave.
Daifeng.
South.
Five li.
Toad Cave.
Major.
We caught a shepherd.
Go.
Old man, let me ask you.
Is there
a place called Toad Cave nearby?
Don't be afraid, old man.
Tell me, and I'll let you go home.
Sir, I really don't know.
Do you live in a nearby village?
I do live in the village.
My family has lived there for generations.
Is this place called Daifeng?
Yes, it's Daifeng.
There is a Toad Cave within five li south of Daifeng.
Don't you know?
There is a cave ahead.
We locals call it Chanchu Cave.
Chanchu Cave.
Tahara, what is Chanchu?
To the Chinese,
toad and Chanchu are the same animal.
Toad is colloquial, and Chanchu is formal.
That's great.
We finally found it.
Thank you, sir. Thank you, sir.
Fall in!
Go.
Come.
We've looked around for ages and found nothing.
It doesn't look like a place where gold is hidden.
Could this gold treasure actually be a gold mine?
A gold mine?
Yeah.
This doesn't look like a treasure trove.
It doesn't even have a door.
If it were a place to hide gold,
there would at least be a secret room.
But there are absolutely no signs
of artificial construction here.
Let's look further ahead.
If it really is a gold mine,
compared to finding hidden gold,
it would be much more valuable.
Mr. Tahara.
It's gold.
Great.
This is a gold mine.
The gold content is very high.
I finally found it.
Officer, please don't arrest him. Don't arrest him.
I won't go. Don't arrest me.
Hurry up.
Go over there.
Hurry.
You still need to be careful with your wound.
It's fine.
Didn't the doctor just say
it's nothing serious?
Hurry up.
Get up.
Don't be reckless.
There are Japanese soldiers everywhere.
But we can't just watch
them arrest innocent people.
They are arresting people everywhere today.
It's so unusual.
Let's follow them
and see what they're up to.
Okay.
Hurry up.
Move it.
Go.
Hurry up.
Who is this person
wearing shackles and handcuffs?
This man is the sixth boss of the Sandaoyuan bandits.
I originally wanted to use him
to recruit more swordsmen for my use.
But he'd rather die than submit,
and he is highly skilled in martial arts.
So I put shackles and handcuffs on him
just in case.
You did the right thing.
For these disobedient Chinese,
we should let them suffer more.
Listen up!
Here,
you are serving our Great Japanese Holy War.
Only by completing the work here diligently
can you qualify to leave.
I advise you not to harbor any illusions.
For those who slack off
or attempt to escape,
we will impose the severest punishment,
even taking your lives.
Of course,
for those who are hardworking and dedicated,
we will also give appropriate rewards.
I hope you behave yourselves.
Take them inside and start working immediately.
You.
Hurry up.
Mr. Tahara did an excellent job.
With this gold mine,
we can alleviate our army's
financial strain.
Hurry up. Move faster.
Keep moving.
In this attack on Qinglong Stronghold,
even though we blew up the enemy's armory,
Master Liu and many of our brothers
lost their lives.
Now Chief Wu's fate
is also unknown.
I have been reflecting since I came back.
My plan wasn't thorough enough.
I bear a lot of responsibility.
Baozi.
Victory and defeat are common in war.
Sacrifices are inevitable in battle.
Besides,
your operation this time
dealt a heavy blow to Tianyuan.
It wasn't a failure.
Old Xu.
Seeing you puts my mind at ease.
Let's discuss
our next move.
Come.
You're back.
Miss.
Baozi.
Where have you two been?
We were worried for a long time.
Yeah.
The Japanese are arresting people everywhere today.
Yuanshangfei and I went to check it out,
and found out
the Japanese are mining for gold.
And they also captured civilians
to use as forced labor.
We also saw Chief Wu.
He is still alive.
Uncle Liu is still alive.
Yes.
He looks like he suffered a lot,
but luckily nothing serious.
So,
Masao Tahara found the location of the gold mine.
It seems so for now.
We can't let the Japs get away with this.
We must find a way
to take it back.
Now that the Japanese army has occupied all of Sandaoyuan,
taking back the gold mine is impossible.
The only way is to destroy it.
It's a good idea,
but impossible to execute.
The Japanese army is heavily guarding the area around the gold mine.
This won't work, that won't work.
The Japs have men, guns, and money.
What do we have?
Are we just waiting to be beaten?
Losing the gold mine
already makes me feel like I failed my father.
If it really becomes the Japanese's funding,
I won't have the face to see my father even when I die.
Whether we are worthy of the Chief
cannot be measured by a gold mine.
But by carrying the resistance against Japan to the end.
Wenpei is right.
Although Sandaoyuan has fallen,
Shanzhou City, Qinglong Stronghold, and Qinfoye Gully
have also fallen into Japanese hands.
The resistance forces in our hands are also limited.
But the other swordsmen in Sandaoyuan are still here.
The vast majority of them
are still resisting Japan.
If we can unite them,
it will be a considerable resistance force.
Right.
Even a tiger takes a nap.
I don't believe,
with the Japs stretching their front lines so long,
they can protect everything.
When the time comes, we will target their weak spots.
Tell me, how do we fight?
Use our swordsmen's familiarity with the terrain
to launch guerrilla attacks on the Japanese army.
Block their main traffic routes,
so their military supplies
cannot smoothly pass through Sandaoyuan.
As long as their main forces are unable to advance west,
it is our victory.
Yuanshangfei.
We are good at this.
Leave the gold mine to me.
I'll find a way to sneak in,
and scout the situation inside.
Yes, let's do that.
Baozi, the car is here.
Right on time.
Brothers, take cover on both sides.
Hurry.
Hurry up.
Take cover, move fast.
Fire!
This is good stuff.
I've wanted it for a long time.
Finally got my hands on it today.
What's this?
When I was in the Eighth Route Army,
I captured a Type 92 artillery from the Japanese.
When that thing fired,
it could blow off a corner of Shanzhou City.
Aren't you going to give one to the eldest miss?
Don't blame me for not reminding you.
She has loved martial arts since she was a child.
If you give her one,
she will definitely be happy.
Why give it to her?
You didn't let her fight the ambush this morning,
she sulked all morning.
She tortured me a lot this morning.
She is too impatient.
She's not suitable for such a patient operation.
There will be plenty of opportunities in the future.
These things are collective property.
When we go back, we have to distribute them according to needs.
Yuanshangfei, your marksmanship is so accurate.
It's a pity for you to use a machine gun.
Don't even think about it this time.
You kid.
Boss.
Boss, what is this?
This is good stuff.
It's called canned food.
It's full of meat.
When the Japanese army marches and fights,
this is what they eat.
The meat inside
won't go bad for months.
That's great.
The brothers have been eating wild vegetables for several meals.
Now we can finally have some meat.
We can't stay here too long.
Otherwise, it will be dangerous.
Brothers, get in the car and let's go.
Let's go.
Report.
Cai Baozi and his swordsmen
blew up our supply truck.
They are now fleeing towards Dawang Town.
Our patrol is pursuing them.
Bastards.
This is the sixth time this month.
The Communists are really annoying.
Just like mosquitoes,
they bite you when you're not paying attention.
Pass on the order.
Send another squadron to reinforce the patrol.
If necessary, wipe out the villages and towns.
Cai Baozi.
I will send all your bandits to hell.
Brigade Commander,
I heard Zhang Gongyan is back.
That was fast.
They say he was snubbed
and came back furious.
And another thing.
The Japanese army in Dawang Town area
clashed with Cai Baozi's swordsmen.
Oh no.
Cai Baozi and his men are targeted by the Japanese.
Cai Baozi initiated it
and destroyed the Japanese supply convoy.
What was he thinking?
Having swordsmen fight the Japanese with broadswords and matchlocks?
You know him.
He'd storm Luoyang single-handedly.
He'd ambush Qinglong Mountain with just a few swords.
Let alone a convoy.
He's got guts.
How are they now?
Currently, Cai Baozi is trapped
in a village west of Dawang Town.
The situation is against them.
No.
Cai Zhen might still be there.
Assemble the troops and get ready to move out anytime.
Why is Cai Zhen there?
Division Commander,
where are you going with my men?
Division Commander, I heard you were back.
I didn't have time to see you yet.
Division Commander, I have an emergency.
I need to save someone.
To save communists like Cai Zhen and Cai Baozi?
Have you lost your mind?
What does their life or death have to do with us?
Is it worth it for just a few of them
to risk our lives fighting the Japanese?
Yes.
They are communists.
But they are fighting the Japanese too.
They are fighting bloody battles against the Japs.
We can't just sit and do nothing.
The Japanese have long wanted to swallow up our 16th Division.
Wouldn't we be walking right into a trap if we go now?
We are soldiers.
Soldiers should defend their country.
Commander.
Shanzhou City has already been lost.
If we don't show up for a small battle like this,
are we worthy of this uniform?
If you want to gain a foothold in the army
and speak with confidence,
you rely on strength.
As long as you have strength,
others will look up to you.
This 16th Division
is what I have worked hard for so many years
to build up.
If they're wiped out
and swallowed up,
what responsibility is there to talk about?
This matter isn't worth it no matter how you calculate it.
Not worth it.
Commander Zhang.
A soldier's duty
is a business in your eyes.
Okay.
I give the 16th Division back to you.
I'll take my leave.
Where are you going?
Commander Zhang, your 16th Division is too precious.
I can't afford to use it.
I'm going back to my Independent Brigade.
Cui Wenkui, don't forget.
Your Independent Brigade is also under the dispatch of my 16th Division.
You also have to obey my orders.
Yes.
Soldiers should obey orders.
But I would rather die on the battlefield
than be a slave of a subjugated nation.
Cui Wenkui.
Don't think your high-sounding words
can cover up your shameful secrets.
I have already investigated it clearly.
That Communist named Cai Zhen
is your biological sister, Cui Wenpei.
Her identity is
the special commissioner of the Eighth Route Army's office in western Henan.
When you escorted her to the prison,
you were knocked out.
That was you letting her go.
At first,
I thought you had a deep brother-sister bond
and you were just momentarily confused.
Only now do I know
that you have truly been communized by the Communist Party.
How dare you openly defy your superiors.
Men!
Arrest Cui Wenkui!
I'd like to see who dares!
I, Cui Wenkui,
have never done anything
to betray the Party and the State.
I will go with you.
Take him away.
Commander.
Here.
Go call that bastard
Zhang Gongyan here.
Yes, sir.
I'll shoot him dead.
That's enough.
Get out.
What are you doing?
You need to calm down.
You are my adjutant now.
With me gone, the whole unit depends on you.
If something happens to you,
what will our brothers do?
Commander.
There is no Independent Brigade anymore.
Zhang Gongyan's men have long controlled it.
He's telling everyone you're a traitor.
The brothers don't know what to do.
Sit down.
Sit.
How many years have you been with me?
Eight years.
I have to be honest with you about something.
Zhang Gongyan said Cai Zhen is a Communist.
He's right.
Cai Zhen is the one I told you about,
my biological sister I've been looking for,
Cui Wenpei.
So I went soft.
Yes, she is a Communist.
But I had no choice.
She is my sister.
I had to help her.
An eldest brother is like a father.
Can you understand?
But don't worry about this.
I, Cui Wenkui, will never implicate
any brothers in our brigade.
As long as I stand firm against Zhang Gongyan,
he won't do anything to me.
When the higher-ups send someone down,
Zhang Gongyan won't be arrogant for long.
He won't do anything to you?
Look at how badly you were beaten.
You are the Commander.
And he still dared to hit you so hard.
If, and I mean if,
before the Commander orders your release,
Zhang Gongyan does something to harm you again,
what should we do?
I believe there is still justice.
Zhang Gongyan is a minority after all.
Justice?
If there was justice,
would you still be here?
Commander.
You gave me this life.
You carried me out of the dead bodies.
You trained me yourself.
In my eyes,
there is only your kindness.
I can do anything for you.
Come back.
What a fool.
Thank goodness you got out unscathed this time.
This gun I've wanted for so long,
I finally captured it.
What gun? Not going to give it to me?
Nothing.
Yuanshang Fei, give yours to me.
Miss.
Anyway, I can't give you mine.
I captured two of them at the time.
I took one,
and Baozi took the other.
He said he would give that one to you.
But he turned around and gave it to that swordsman.
Really?
Come here, come here.
Explain it to me clearly.
Have some water.
No.
Yuanshangfei, I think you have
the potential to be a traitor.
I told you not to mention it.
Why did you sell me out behind my back?
I...
Okay, I see how it is.
Ganging up on me, huh?
If you don't get me a better one anyway,
you have to give me yours.
Fine.
I'll get you one next time.
Commissioner Cui.
Adjutant Zhu from the Independent Brigade is here to see you.
Wenpei.
Please save our brigade commander.
What happened?
Our commander heard that your guerrillas
were fighting the Japanese around Dawang Town.
He wanted to come and help.
Who knew that Zhang Gongyan
got a rebuff from somewhere,
and took his anger out on our commander.
He arrested him as soon as he came back.
What did you say?
Zhang Gongyan arrested Cui Wenkui?
Yes.
He said it was because of Wenpei's influence
that he betrayed the party and joined the Communists.
He is now locked in prison and being tortured
to force our commander
into making a false confession.
This Zhang Gongyan
It's not the first time he's made things difficult for my brother.
Now he's doing it again.
Although this trick looks old-fashioned,
it is very effective.
The Kuomintang has always been afraid
of the growing strength of the Communist Party.
Many officers
have been imprisoned for being pro-Communist.
Our commander hasn't seen through their tricks yet.
He still thinks the higher-ups will give him justice.
But I know clearly
that Zhang Gongyan won't let him go this time.
He is going to be ruthless.
Before, when I was a Juntong major,
there might have been a way.
Now that my identity is exposed,
it's very hard to intervene.
Moreover, the Party organization strictly requires
us to maintain the overall situation of the resistance.
We can't have any friction with the Kuomintang,
to avoid giving the Japanese an opportunity
for their westward advance.
Even if I want to save my brother,
I can't find a suitable way.
If,
if none of you can help,
then no one can save our commander.
Let me think about it.
Xu,
take Adjutant Zhu to rest first.
Alright.
Let's go, Adjutant Zhu.
It's fine.
I wonder how Wenkui
is doing right now.
Baozi, I can tell
that Wenpei wants to save her brother.
Yes.
But some bottom lines cannot be crossed.
Crossing them will cause chaos,
and more people will get hurt.
No one can afford this price.
Is this what my father meant
by 'loyalty and righteousness cannot both be preserved'?
Exactly.
When I was in the Eighth Route Army,
I often saw my comrades surrounded by the enemy.
But because we had missions,
we couldn't go and save them.
Until the moment of their sacrifice,
these comrades couldn't even see their families one last time.
Sacrificing one's own family for the greater good
is not what we wish for.
If not,
our country won't see the light.
I understand all that.
But I can't bear to see her suffer.
I am not in the Eighth Route Army.
I can still save people, right?
Seems so.
Okay.
Then I'll take my brothers.
I'll take the blame if anything happens.
Cui Wenpei must not know about this.
It must be done quietly.
So you mean...
I'll go with you.
You...
I, Shangguan Ying, was not wrong about you.
My man
is indeed righteous and loyal.